<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hacking-that-camps-yack on Amanda Regan</title>
    <link>https://www.amanda-regan.com/tags/hacking-that-camps-yack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hacking-that-camps-yack on Amanda Regan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 14:30:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.amanda-regan.com/tags/hacking-that-camps-yack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THATCamp Topic Modeling Results</title>
      <link>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/thatcamp-topic-modeling-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 14:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/thatcamp-topic-modeling-results/</guid>
      <description>This post is the last in a set of 5 written by the Digital History Fellows at the Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media. The original post, which was collectively written by the DH Fellows, can be found on our Digital History Fellowship Blog.
We have spent the last few weeks working to build a python script that would allow us to download and prep all of the THATCamp blog posts for topic modeling in MALLET (for those catching up, we detailed this process in a series of previous posts).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected Challenges Result in Important and Informative Discussions: a transparent discussion about stripping content and stopwords</title>
      <link>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/unexpected-challenges-result-important-informative-discussions-transparent-discussion-stripping-content-stopwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/unexpected-challenges-result-important-informative-discussions-transparent-discussion-stripping-content-stopwords/</guid>
      <description>This post is the fourth in a set of 5 written by the Digital History Fellows at the Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media. The original post by Jannelle Legg can be found on the Digital History Fellowship Blog.
As described in previous posts, the first year Digital Fellows at CHNM have been working on a project under the Research division that involves collecting, cleaning, and analyzing data from a corpus of THATCamp content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Processing Text for MALLET</title>
      <link>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/pre-processing-text-mallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 14:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/pre-processing-text-mallet/</guid>
      <description>This post is the third in a set of 5 written by the Digital History Fellows at the Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media. The original post can be found on the Digital History Fellowship Blog.
In our previous post, we described the process of writing a python script that pulled from the THATCamp MySQL Database. In this post, we will continue with this project and work to clean up the data we&amp;rsquo;ve collected and prepare it for some analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Data from the THATCamp Database Using Python and MySQL</title>
      <link>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/extracting-data-python-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 20:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/extracting-data-python-mysql/</guid>
      <description>This post is the second in a set of 4 written by the Digital History Fellows at the Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media. The original post can be found on the Digital History Fellowship Blog.
This week we&amp;rsquo;ve continued to work on building a python script that will extract all of the blog posts from the various THATCamp websites. As Jannelle described last week, our goal was to write a script that downloads the blog posts in plain text form and strips all of the html tags, stopwords, and punctuation so that we can feed it into MALLET for topic modeling and text analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Semester in Research and a THATCamp Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/spring-semester-research-thatcamp-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 19:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amanda-regan.com/posts/spring-semester-research-thatcamp-challenge/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first in a set of 4 written by the Digital History Fellows at the Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media. The original post by Jannelle Legg can be found on the Digital History Fellowship Blog.
The spring semester is here and the first year DH fellows have begun our rotation into the Research division of CHNM.
To get the ball rolling, we spent a week working through the helpful tutorials at theProgramming Historian.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
