<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital History Readings Course on Amanda Regan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/digital-history-readings-course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital History Readings Course on Amanda Regan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 03:25:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/digital-history-readings-course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital History Minor Field, Part 5: Topic Modeling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/digital-history-minor-field-part-5-topic-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 03:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/digital-history-minor-field-part-5-topic-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week our readings focused on Topic Modeling. I’ve been looking forward to this week for some time partly because I plan to use Topic Modeling for my dissertation but also because  I was eager to understand some of the theoretical underpinnings of the methodology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the Digital History Fellows in the Research Division  last spring, we were asked to do a &lt;a href=&#34;http://chnm.gmu.edu/courses/fellowship/?p=470&#34;&gt;topic modeling project&lt;/a&gt; on all of the blog posts from the the various THATCamps. We jumped in, attempted to learn python, managed to download every blog post from each THATCamp (well over 200), and then ran that data through MALLET for topic modeling. To make a very long story short, we managed to mess up the topic modeling and, consequently, our results for a variety of reasons. We encountered a number  of challenges but the results were skewed mostly because we didn’t understand the black box that is MALLET. However, although the project turned out to be a mess, I came to the readings this week with a bit of background on topic modeling and have gained a new perspective on the mistakes made during that project. (I think the project also has some lessons regarding failure in the digital humanities, but I’ll come back to that in another blog post.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minor Field Readings, Part 4: Space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/minor-field-readings-part-4-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 19:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/minor-field-readings-part-4-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a few weeks behind with this blog post about our minor field readings meeting on Space in Digital History. For this meeting we read a variety of works that discussed Geographic Information Systems (GIS), spatial history, the possibilities and and the complexities of presenting historical material geographically using digital technology and methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GIS has been around for years now, yet historians have never embraced it like geographers have. Partly, as many of the authors point out, this is because of the software’s need for exact data rather than fuzzy or general information. Geographic coordinates must be exact rather than general which poses a problem for historians who don’t have exact data. Further, the software doesn’t handle change over time, a necessity for historians, well. In the &lt;em&gt;Spatial Humanities: GIS and the Future of Humanities Scholarship&lt;/em&gt; Bodengier et. al. discuss the limitations that GIS has “privileged a certain way of knowing the world, one that valued authority, definition, and certainty over complexity, ambiguity, multiplicity, and contingency….” [1. Bodengier et. al, ix]. This edited volume containing influential voices in the field of GIS, calls for and discusses the ways that GIS must move beyond the quantitative to the qualitative in order to appeal and be of use to historians. However, the emergence of the semantic web, Google Maps and other APIs, as well as Geolocated mobile devices have appealed more to historians looking to geolocate their work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minor Field Readings, Part 3: Changing Theories of History</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/changing-theories-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 22:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/changing-theories-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weeks readings on “Changing Theories of History” discussed the ways digital methods are changing how historians practice or “do” history.  Several authors discussed how digital research methods change the scale of materials that we can draw upon while researching a topic.  Others discussed the possibility of using visualizations to communicate historical arguments rather than narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Armitage and Guildi discuss in their article “The Return of the &lt;em&gt;Longue Duree&lt;/em&gt;: An Anglo-American Perspective” the origins of the Longue Duree and the shift away from histories that seek to tell the grand macro-narrative to the small focused micro-histories of the 1980s.  Braudel, the original advocate of the Longue Duree, argued that histories in cycles of ten or twenty years don’t capture the “deeper regularities and continuities underlying the processes of change.”[1. David Armitage and Jo Guildi, &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.harvard.edu/files/armitage/files/rld_annales_revised_0.pdf&#34;&gt;“The Return of the _Longue Duree: _An Anglo American Perspective”&lt;/a&gt;] Beginning in the 1980s most historians moved away from approaches that focused on large time scales and felt a need to specialize because of the influx of graduate students to the profession.  As a result, micro-history flourished and represented a shift toward “generalization about the aggregate to micro-politics and the successes or failures of particular battles within the larger class struggles.”[2. Armitage and Guildi, 16] Since the 1980s, Historians have continued to write histories that have focused on manageable time spans, narrow topics, or individual locations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minor Field Readings, Part 2: Perspectives on New Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/perspectives-new-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 22:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/perspectives-new-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weeks readings on “Perspectives of New Media” discussed from varying viewpoints how new media is and has changed the ways scholarship is produced and conceptualized. The readings contemplate what new media tools and technologies change for how we think about, produce, and evaluate information.  Out of these readings came a consistent concern with scale, linearity, and how digital technologies and tools will affect narrative, or for my purposes, a historical argument.  The assumption has long been that reputable scholarship, at least for historians, is written, linear, and is composed in a narrative.  That’s what our profession values.  However, this is (hopefully) beginning to change due to new media and how it has fundamentally changed “how we think.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minor Field Readings, Part 1: Digital Humanities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dhs-histories-debates-promises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 11:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dhs-histories-debates-promises/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This summer I am completing a readings course for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amanda-regan.com/digital-history-minor-field/&#34;&gt;minor field in Digital History&lt;/a&gt;.  This weeks readings have discussed the digital humanities, the history of the field, and have offered critiques as well as predictions about where the field is going.  Most volumes about Digital Humanities discuss the history of the field and place its origins in the history of humanities computing.  While there is certainly truth in these accounts, they often overlook the histories of disciplines such as history and how these fields merged together to form the “Digital Humanities” around 2004.  This week&amp;rsquo;s readings have coincided with the recent conversations about the digital humanities by  by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foundhistory.org/2014/04/07/the-dividends-of-difference-recognizing-digital-humanities-diverse-family-trees/&#34;&gt;Tom Schienfelt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://drstephenrobertson.com/2014/05/23/the-differences-between-digital-history-and-digital-humanities/&#34;&gt;Stephen Robertson&lt;/a&gt;. The current discussion about the fragmentation of the Digital Humanities into disciplines makes reading about the debates, critiques, and trends in the Digital Humanities even more interesting.  While history is most certainly part of the digital humanities conversation (and I’m not arguing that it shouldn’t be) I think it is useful to look at the issues in the field from the perspective of an aspiring digital historian and to discuss how they might be relevant to those of us looking to create digital dissertations and those of us preparing to enter the job market in the next six years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readings Course on Digital History in Theory and Practice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/readings-series-digital-history-theory-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 20:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/readings-series-digital-history-theory-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This summer I&amp;rsquo;ll be completing a readings course for my Digital History minor field with Stephen Robertson.  The course will cover Digital History in both Theory and Practice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can view the proposed abstract and bibliography for this course &lt;a href=&#34;http://wp.me/P3WbUx-aR&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  In addition to a traditional readings course, I felt it was important to not only understand the major debates in the field but also to learn practical skills that will aid me as I move toward the dissertation stage.  The practical skills will be achieved by incorporating Clio III: Programming for Historians into the minor field.  I’ll be taking that course in fall 2014 with Lincoln Mullen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
