<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clio Wired I on Amanda Regan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/clio-wired-i/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clio Wired I on Amanda Regan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 15:45:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/clio-wired-i/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Color</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/color/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 15:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/color/</guid>
      <description>The last couple weeks we&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about color and the do&amp;rsquo;s and don&amp;rsquo;ts of picking a color scheme. I think the reading in White Space is Not Your Enemy was very helpful and got me thinking about the color scheme for the design project.&#xA;Something that was extremely useful for me was the explanation of the differences between CMYK, PANTONE, and RGB. Prior to reading this I sort of understood the difference just from experience but the reading really pinpointed what each system is for, when to use it, and how it works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final Digital Scholarship Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/final-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 19:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/final-project/</guid>
      <description>The final version of my Clio Wired Project, &amp;ldquo;Shifts in Physical Culture,&amp;rdquo; is online now. It has been quite the process getting everything formatted correctly&amp;ndash;I realized after I presented that I had made a mistake and did not included all of the articles when I ran the topic modeling software so I had to adjust that. Overall the results are the same&amp;ndash;there is a definite change in the discussion of physical culture between 1932 and 1937.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shifts in Physical Culture: A Textual Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/shifts-physical-culture-textual-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 20:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/shifts-physical-culture-textual-analysis/</guid>
      <description>My work of digital scholarship uses Topic Modeling to analyze a set of articles written by Sylvia Ullback, a beauty expert in the 1930s, between 1932 and 1937. Ullback&amp;rsquo;s articles shift during this period and the change in her discussion of beauty can be seen in the topic models. For more background on Sylvia Ullback and her career see the website for this project. This is a work in progress and I&amp;rsquo;ll give more detail about the changes tonight in class but here is what I have so far:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Humanities and Collaboration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/digital-humanities-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 20:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/digital-humanities-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>Collaboration isn’t new for historians. A piece of historical scholarship has always involved a range of people. The prologue of most traditional monographs includes a list of those who helped make the book possible. From the support and assistance of archivists and librarians, to review and support by fellow scholars and students, and often financial support from institutions and publishers publishing a work of traditional scholarship is by no means an individual endeavor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology and the Classroom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/technology-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 16:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/technology-classroom/</guid>
      <description>I TA’d for the first time last spring, my last semester in my masters program. It was the first time I had ever taught and I quickly learned that leading a discussion section and getting freshman interested in World History was challenging. I came away from the semester realizing, what may be obvious to those more experienced teachers, that teaching history to undergrads from a variety of majors is more difficult that it appears.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Data for Historians</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/big-data-historians/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 17:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/big-data-historians/</guid>
      <description>Franco Moretti’s article “Graphs, Maps, and Trees: Abstract Models for Literary History,” shows how most histories of the book have focused on a few particular books rather than the novel as a genre. This has probably had to do with scale. It would be an overwhelming and almost impossible task to read every single novel in order to write a comprehensive and all-encompassing history of the novel. However, this is where Big Data allows historians to look at large trends in ways that are impractical without computers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Regional Ideals of Beauty, 1900-1940: A Digital Research Resouce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mappingregionalidealsofbeauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 15:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mappingregionalidealsofbeauty/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned a few times before I am interested in ideas about the body and beauty in the early twentieth century. My digital resource is a research tool that would help me to analyze the mass amounts of newspaper articles available.&#xA;Background Between 1900 and 1940 there were several distinct shifts in the ideas of beauty and physical culture for women in the United States. Shifts in the image and role of the New Woman, from the Gibson Girl to the Flapper, were accompanied by changes in the ideal female body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial History as a Research Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/spatial-history-research-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 16:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/spatial-history-research-tool/</guid>
      <description>In Richard White&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;What is Spatial History?,&amp;rdquo; he discusses the turn to spatial history and the ways in which it can be used as a research tool to enhance historical scholarship. His article was fascinating and really got me thinking about different spatial history projects I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. Two that come to mind is &amp;ldquo;Visualizing Emancipation&amp;rdquo;, run by Scott Nesbit and Edward Ayers at the University of Richmond&amp;rsquo;s Digital Scholarship Lab, and The Geography of Hate, run by Monica Stephens at Humboldt State University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examples of Spatial History</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/examples-spatial-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 09:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/examples-spatial-history/</guid>
      <description>I posted these in the Zotero group, but I thought I would add them here as well. I think these are two interesting examples of spatial history. Mapping Decline: St. Louis and the American City is an example of using a spatial history component to bolster an argument. We have been talking about Digital History and whether it needs to make an argument all semester and I think _Mapping Decline _is a great example of a project that does that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Overwhelming Challenge of Preserving Born Digital Materials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/395/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 16:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/395/</guid>
      <description>The Preserving our Digital Heritage: Plan for the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program stated that the average length of a website is 44 days. That really surprised me. I think the preservation of born digital material is an important issue right now, and it&amp;rsquo;s only going to get more important as our world increasingly becomes more digital. It is really an overwhelming issue with so many hurdles and potential issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowdsourced Collections: A Democratic Approach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/crowdsourced-collections-democratic-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 15:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/crowdsourced-collections-democratic-approach/</guid>
      <description>I came across a project of Berry College and Bloomsberg University this week called the Martha Berry Digital Archive. The site is built on Omeka and a plugin the developers created for the site called &amp;ldquo;Crowd-Ed&amp;rdquo;. The plugin allows the digitization of their entire collection to be crowdsourced. In other words, the archive digitizes the documents and users annotate, tag, and fill in the metadata for each item.&#xA;Crowdsourcing has been gaining popularity recently and has become a way for archives to digitize mass amounts of data fairly quickly and at a minimal cost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Access, Open Source, and the Responsibilities of Historians in the Digital World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/open-access-open-source-responsibilities-historians-digital-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/open-access-open-source-responsibilities-historians-digital-world/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended WordCamp Baltimore, a WordPress developers conference. Aaron Jorbin, a well-known WordPress developer in the D.C. area, gave the keynote address which was about open source platforms and the open source community. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with the &amp;ldquo;.org&amp;rdquo; version of WordPress, it is open source and free to anyone who wants to use, modify, or develop the software. Jorbin&amp;rsquo;s keynote was entitled &amp;ldquo;Citizenship in the Open Source World&amp;rdquo; and he talked a lot about the responsibilities and the rights of a citizen in the &amp;ldquo;Open Source World.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webdesign for Academics </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/webdesign-for-academics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 18:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/webdesign-for-academics/</guid>
      <description>Web Design is not something academic are traditionally trained in. However, as the discipline continues to change and Digital History continues to develop and grow, knowing a little bit about what constitutes a good historical website is necessary.&#xA;Alexander Dawson makes excellent points about the development and organization of a website in his article &amp;ldquo;Improve Usability by Studying Museums.&amp;rdquo; He compares the layout of a museum to that of a website and argues that many web designers could take some tips from the organization of museums.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the digital humanities, what do they do, and how does digital history fit in?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-are-the-digital-humanities-what-do-they-do-and-how-does-digital-history-fit-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 15:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-are-the-digital-humanities-what-do-they-do-and-how-does-digital-history-fit-in/</guid>
      <description>What are the digital humanities, what do they do, and how does digital history fit in? It’s a valid question and one that I think has several answers.Northwestern University’s “A Guide to Digital Humanities”confronts this question and attempts to make sense of the many different definitions that exist for Digital Humanities. The consensus seems to be that the Digital Humanities are centered on scholarship. The digital humanities are both a methodology and a presentation technique.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clio I--Introduction and RSS Feeds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/clio-i-introduction-and-rss-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 20:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/clio-i-introduction-and-rss-feeds/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be using this website as my blog for Clio I this fall at George Mason University.&#xA;I am a PhD student and Digital History Fellow at George Mason University. My research interest is primarily U.S. Women’s history with a particular focus on physical culture and beauty in the early twentieth century as well as Digital History. As part of the Digital History Fellowship I will be working in the Center for History and Media at GMU for the next few years.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
