<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on Amanda Regan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on Amanda Regan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>History 8500: Methods in Digital History I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/8500spring25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/8500spring25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to History 8500, Methods in Digital History I. This course in computational history will teach you to create, manipulate, explore, and visualize historical data with the goal of advancing historical arguments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course will proceed in roughly 3 units. In the first students will learn to navigate their computer using the command line, learn file system structure and basic server architecture, and will learn how to use GitHub to ensure reproducible datasets and code. Students will also be introduced to static websites and will begin a semester long project of building a personal website and portfolio in the static website software Hugo. The next unit focuses on the basics of the programming with an emphasis on computational thinking skills and the foundational patterns behind every programming language. Finally, in the last half of our course, we will survey various methods within computational history and ask ourselves, what kinds of historical questions do these methods make possible? Each week will focus on a new method &amp;ndash; visualization, mapping, and several forms of text analysis. By the end of this course, you&amp;rsquo;ll have gained a basic familiarity and competency all of these approaches, but &lt;strong&gt;more importantly&lt;/strong&gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll understand how to ask and answer historical questions using the computational methods that are useful to you. While not required, it is best to take this course alongside History 8550: Theories of Digital Analysis which has been designed to complement the topics in this class and provide a theoretical and scholarly underpinning for the methods we learn in class.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 1020: United States History, 1877-Present</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/1020spring24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/1020spring24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course surveys the history of the United States, beginning with the end of the Civil War  and ending in the modern day. By the end of this course, students will have obtained a solid understanding of the major events and forces in American history. Throughout the course we will pay close attention to the major political, social, and economic movements of the late 19th and early 20th centuries. Additionally we will disrupt the traditional narrative of American history by focusing on the many &lt;em&gt;histories&lt;/em&gt; of the United States. Relying heavily on both textual and visual primary sources, we will spend this semester looking at the major events in U.S. history not as points in a singular and linear narrative but rather a series of interwoven stories driven by a diverse set of actors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 8510: Methods in Digital History II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/8510spring24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/8510spring24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to History 8510, Methods in Digital History II. This course in computational history will teach you to create, manipulate, explore, and visualize historical data with the goal of advancing historical arguments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This class is the second in a series of digital history courses at Clemson University. It is designed to build on History 8500: Digital Methods I. In that course you reviewed digital history projects and methods, experimented with out of the box tools, and developed your own digital research collections. In this course we will build on that and you will now learn to use computational methods to analyze historical sources in the programming language R.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 8550: Seminar in Digital History</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/8550fall23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/8550fall23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History 8550 is a seminar in digital history where students will create a piece of digital scholarship that uses digital history methods to advance a historical argument. Students will work in collaboration with the course instructor and their primary advisor to come up with a project that uses digital methods to advance a historiographical interpretation. Unlike a traditional seminar paper, this paper will likely have multiple components (a dataset, narrative writing piece, and code).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 8850: Independent Study</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/8850fall23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/8850fall23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This independent study is meant to provide an overview of the major historical and historiographical developments in the study of women’s history. Each week you will attend &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/courses/3180fall23&#34;&gt;History 3180&lt;/a&gt; and participate in class lectures and activities. This is designed to give you an overview of some of the major events, themes, and idea in women’s history. You will also read a selection of important works in the field of US History and attend the Berkshire Women’s History Conference. In addition to coming to the undergraduate meetings of History 3180, you will also meet individually with me every other Friday and we will discuss the readings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 8510: Methods in Digital History II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/8510spring23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/8510spring23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to History 8510, Methods in Digital History II. This course in computational history will teach you to create, manipulate, explore, and visualize historical data with the goal of advancing historical arguments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This class is the second in a series of digital history courses at Clemson University. It is designed to build on History 8500: Digital Methods I. In that course you reviewed digital history projects and methods, experimented with out of the box tools, and developed your own digital research collections. In this course we will build on that and you will now learn to use computational methods to analyze historical sources in the programming language R.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 3050: The United States, 1918-1945</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/3050spring23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/3050spring23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome! This course will explore American History between the years of 1918 and 1945. Bookended by World War I and World War II, we&amp;rsquo;ll examine the profound social, cultural, and political changes that occurred in American life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The course begins in the midst of a world war and a crushing pandemic before moving into what has been described as the &amp;ldquo;Roaring Twenties.&amp;rdquo; We&amp;rsquo;ll interrogate this period and ask how the pandemic, war, and expansion of the American state under Prohibition changed America. Paying attention to the diversity of Americans&amp;rsquo; experiences in the twenties, we will ask for whom was the 1920s &amp;ldquo;roaring&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 3050: The United States, 1918-1945</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/3050fall22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/3050fall22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome! This course will explore American History between the years of 1918 and 1945. Bookended by World War I and World War II, we&amp;rsquo;ll examine the profound social, cultural, and political changes that occurred in American life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The course begins in the midst of a world war and a crushing pandemic before moving into what has been described as the &amp;ldquo;Roaring Twenties.&amp;rdquo; We&amp;rsquo;ll interrogate this period and ask how the pandemic, war, and expansion of the American state under Prohibition changed America. Paying attention to the diversity of Americans&amp;rsquo; experiences in the twenties, we will ask for whom was the 1920s &amp;ldquo;roaring&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 1010: US History to 1877</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/1010spring22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/1010spring22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History 1010 covers the political, economic, and social development of the American people from the period of discovery to the end of Reconstruction. Includes Honors sections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this course we will explore American history beginning with the initial settlement of the continent and ending with the Civil War. Rather than covering every detail and event within this period, the course will focus on providing a broad overview of how the United States came to be, the major forces shaping its development, and the significance of Colonial America. Students will leave this class with a basic understanding of the major turning points and events in American History to 1865 and will study how political, economic, social, intellectual, cultural, and religious changes shaped the development of the early United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 8510: Methods in Digital History II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/computationalhistory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/computationalhistory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-secondary&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;i&gt; This is a sample syllabus for History 8510: Methods in Digital History II at Clemson University. If you would like to view the online version of this syllabus you can do so at www.amanda-regan.com/courses/computationalhistory.&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to History 8510, Methods in Digital History II. This course in computational history will teach you to create, manipulate, explore, and visualize historical data with the goal of advancing historical arguments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This class is the second in a series of digital history courses at Clemson University. It is designed to build on History 8500: Digital Methods I. In that course you reviewed digital history projects and methods, experimented with out of the box tools, and developed your own digital research collections. In this course we will build on that and you will now learn to use computational methods to analyze historical sources in the programming language R.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History 1010: US History to 1877</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/courses/1010fall21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/courses/1010fall21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History 1010 covers the political, economic, and social development of the American people from the period of discovery to the end of Reconstruction. Includes Honors sections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-overview&#34;&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this course we will explore American history beginning with the initial settlement of the continent and ending with the Civil War. Rather than covering every detail and event within this period, the course will focus on providing a broad overview of how the United States came to be, the major forces shaping its development, and the significance of Colonial America. Students will leave this class with a basic understanding of the major turning points and events in American History to 1865 and will study how political, economic, social, intellectual, cultural, and religious changes shaped the development of the early United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
