<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on Amanda Regan</title>
    <link>https://amanda-regan.com/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on Amanda Regan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amanda-regan.com/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>History 3890: Mapping the Gay Guides</title>
      <link>https://amanda-regan.com/courses/3890spring22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-regan.com/courses/3890spring22/</guid>
      <description>Course Overview In this creative inquiry course students will work on Mapping the Gay Guides, a digital history project that seeks to digitize LGBTQ guidebooks from the 1960s through the 1990s. While on his frequent business trips around the United States in the late 1950s and early 1960s, Bob Damron wanted to find bars and other locales to meet other men like him. A gay man, Damron sought friends, companions, and safety at friendly businesses in the various cities he visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History 8510: Methods in Digital History II</title>
      <link>https://amanda-regan.com/courses/computationalhistory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-regan.com/courses/computationalhistory/</guid>
      <description>This is a sample syllabus for History 8510: Methods in Digital History II at Clemson University. If you would like to view the online version of this syllabus you can do so at www.amanda-regan.com/courses/computationalhistory.  Course Description Welcome to History 8510, Methods in Digital History II. This course in computational history will teach you to create, manipulate, explore, and visualize historical data with the goal of advancing historical arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History 1010: US History to 1877</title>
      <link>https://amanda-regan.com/courses/1010spring22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amanda-regan.com/courses/1010spring22/</guid>
      <description>Course Overview History 1010 covers the political, economic, and social development of the American people from the period of discovery to the end of Reconstruction. Includes Honors sections.
In this course we will explore American history beginning with the initial settlement of the continent and ending with the Civil War. Rather than covering every detail and event within this period, the course will focus on providing a broad overview of how the United States came to be, the major forces shaping its development, and the significance of Colonial America.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
